

Sakari Cajanus scajanus@gmail.com sakaricajanus.com +358503083440

In January 2017, I left Finland to do something else for a while.

I worked on Cat Ba in Vietnam as a guide for climbing and kayaking, and then traveled and climbed in Middle East and South East Asia.

When I got a job in the field again, I wondering how good I still was.

Pretty good.

Now I am in Berlin, in the future either here or someplace else.

Sakari Cajanus

Data Scientist - Curriculum Vitae

About Me I have a degree in Biomedical Engineering from Aalto University, where I studied modelling biological networks and computational genomics. Since then, I have used the knowledge in the field of marine industry and opinion research. I have worked in research, and as an analyst, product manager and software developer.

I made this: DWS tide calendar. It combines tidal data from worldtides.info API, pokes at it, and presents it as a calendar and daily plots.

Experience

June 2018 - now, Product Owner of Data and Statistics, Civey GmbH

- I was responsible for Recommendation engine, population data and vote data packages.
- Built a new recommendation engine based on a hidden Markov Model from scratch to production with Python and gRPC, along with several working prototypes on the way using Flask
- Built several small services that involved getting data from a database, transforming it or performing rudimentary modeling, and presenting as a web app

February 2017 - August 2017, Adventure Guide, Asia Outdoors

• Good for water cooler talk. And team events, if you want to go climbing.

February 2014 – January 2017, *Several positions*, Eniram Ltd. Product manager:

- Product management of Models and Data Processing teams, product owner of statistical models and data processing software
- Worked with other product managers and CTO to satisfy customer needs, prioritize development tasks and deliver on time

Software developer:

- Developed software for data analysis in Python and Matlab
- Moved software to production, planned roadmaps
- Developed minimum viable product for delivering push notifications from Matlab (!) to a mobile app.

Analyst:

- Delivered reports to customers on time and with accuracy
- Tracked, diagnosed and fixed data quality issues
- Focus on fuel savings and system usage, including comparisons between vessels

June 2013 – November 2013, *Master's Thesis Worker*, Polar Electro Oy

Studied the data and the extent to which it is used in the company. Identified opportunities where data could be used to improve customer experience and marketing.

May 2011 – Dec 2012, Research Assistant at BECS, Aalto University Used point pattern and spatial models for human communication and nerve fiber data. Used both MATLAB and R for statistical analysis.



Sakari Cajanus scajanus@gmail.com sakaricajanus.com +358503083440

In January 2017, I left Finland to do something else for a while.

I worked on Cat Ba in Vietnam as a guide for climbing and kayaking, and then traveled and climbed in Middle East and South East Asia.

When I got a job in the field again, I wondering how good I still was.

Pretty good.

Now I am in Berlin, in the future either here or someplace else.

Education

2015, Aalto University

Master of Science (Tech.) in Bioinformation Technology

2012, Aalto University

Bachelor of Science (Tech.) in Bioinformation Technology

Tech skills

At work and at home

PythonSQLRgRPCFlasketc.

In the past

o C/C++ o Matlab o Java

Soft tech skills

Unit testing, git, I'm pretty good in vim and can write a mean regex.

I would like to refresh my statistics and linear algebra, as well as keep doing small things for web.

Positions of Trust

2016, Vice Chairman, Contractura climbing club2016, Member of Delegation, Medical student association2011, Member of the Board, Inkubio ry., student association

Language skills

Fluent

Finnish, English as work language for 7 years

Conversational

German – can follow most conversations, speak basic German Swedish – the same, but worse